<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Julian Ceipek</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects.html</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Julian Ceipek</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//jceipek.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Auraline</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/auraline.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/auraline.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Aurora</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/aurora.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/aurora.html</guid><description>Aurora is an interactive kinetic ceiling that changes its configuration in response to what is happening in the space beneath it.
I developed software to simulate the ceiling virtually while also driving the motors that control it physically. I worked closely with Behnaz Farahi to design depth camera-driven procedural animations for the ceiling.</description></item><item><title>Callbacks &amp; Scoping with Python and JS</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/async.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/async.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Caress of the Gaze</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/cog.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/cog.html</guid><description>Behnaz Farahi&amp;rsquo;s Caress of the Gaze is a dress that changes shape when people look at it, exploring social issues such as intimacy, gender and personal identity. It has been featured by outlets including Wired, CNN, The Guardian, BBC News, Engadget, and CNET.
I developed the control software for the final iteration of the dress. Along the way, I&amp;hellip;
created a reusable C library to communicate with a privacy-preserving face tracking camera, which I&amp;rsquo;ve since used on many other projects worked closely with Behnaz to design reactive procedural animations driven by gaze-tracking data learned how to control shape memory alloy actuators that expand and contract like muscles</description></item><item><title>Complete Galactic Dominion</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/cgd.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/cgd.html</guid><description>In 2011, I took an introductory software design class at Olin, where I first learned Python and how to collaborate on non-trivial programming projects.
My team&amp;rsquo;s final project was Complete Galactic Dominion (CGD), an (over)ambitious real-time strategy game played on a toroidal map (the playing area doesn&amp;rsquo;t have defined boundaries but wraps around like old arcade games like Pac-Man).
By the time the class ended, CGD had one working resource, building, and unit type and theoretical support for an arbitrary number of networked players playing on different operating systems.</description></item><item><title>Cracking ElGamal for fun and profit</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/elgamal.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/elgamal.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dark</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/dark.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/dark.html</guid><description>The Dark programming environment provides the easiest way to make a simple backend web service. Its holistic design makes it possible to safely program against live data, see the result of every data transformation, interact with third party web APIs, and read/write to databases &amp;mdash; all from the same interface.
As an engineer at Dark (the company), I&amp;hellip;
developed, documented, and tested Dark&amp;rsquo;s standard programming library &amp;mdash; the toolkit with which customers build software used by tens of thousands of end users.</description></item><item><title>Daunting Dollhouse</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/dauntingdollhouse.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/dauntingdollhouse.html</guid><description>Daunting Dollhouse is a rapid asymmetric two-player battle of wits and observation that pits a ghost against a ghost hunter. It arose from an interesting design constraint: what if players share a single screen that gives them each different hidden information?
The players each secretly control one of six funky dolls and try to conceal their identities by pretending to be computer-controlled characters. The ghost can switch between the bodies of different dolls while the hunter attempts to catch the ghost by listening for paranormal activity.</description></item><item><title>effect</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/effect.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/effect.html</guid><description>I created effect as a 2 week experiment in large scale, local multi-person, multi-display interactions. Thirteen participants connected to a web app displaying a simple pipe puzzle and needed to collaborate in order to guide a ball through a maze. Each participant could rotate a single randomly assigned pipe in the puzzle by clicking on their screen, but they were not given any additional feedback. One additional computer projected a special version of the puzzle on a large projection screen.</description></item><item><title>Empowering Manufacturers with X-ray Vision</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/x-ray-vision.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/x-ray-vision.html</guid><description>Most of the world&amp;rsquo;s manufacturers rely on inadequate tools to identify and fix problems with their products: they commonly cut samples of their products in half hoping to find defects that might also exist in the units they don&amp;rsquo;t destroy. At Lumafield, I collaboratively developed approachable X-ray tools that empower manufacturers of any size to affordably find problems inside their products without destroying them. I improved every part of Lumafield&amp;rsquo;s software stack over the course of three years:</description></item><item><title>engulf</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/engulf.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/engulf.html</guid><description>You can&amp;rsquo;t really know if something is usable without using it. After making pyShiva, I wanted to use it to make something I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have easily made without it, and so I spent a day making a game demo. At the same time, I wanted to experiment with gesture-based interfaces.
The result: engulf, a frantic quest to consume nutrients and grow larger while escaping a cloud of enemies.
The gameplay and control scheme are finely tuned to take advantage of the Kinect; you must change your avatar&amp;rsquo;s appearance and size in order to eat food of the appropriate color while dodging between narrow gaps formed by the enemies harrowing you at every turn.</description></item><item><title>Evil Lairs for Dummies</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/evillairsfordummiesgame.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/evillairsfordummiesgame.html</guid><description>Evil Lairs for Dummies is a game that promotes quick thinking and out-of-the-box creative problem solving within a loose storytelling framework.
You play as masterful team of super creative agents on a top secret mission. You retrieved The Great Mcguffin, and now you&amp;rsquo;re trying to escape from the Evil Supervillain&amp;rsquo;s Lair. The Lair is filled with deadly traps that you have to overcome as a team.
Variant 1 : Team vs Clock!</description></item><item><title>Game Path Planning</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/gamepathplanning.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/gamepathplanning.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Installation Visualizer</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/installation-visualizer.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/installation-visualizer.html</guid><description>In 2021, I designed and led Beyond the Grid: Interactive Installations with Wacky Topologies for the DigitalFUTURES festival together with my longtime collaborator Behnaz Farahi. During the week-long workshop, we remotely taught 14 students around the globe (including Greece, China, England, Iran, and the US) how to design, build, and program interactive art sculptures with unusual shapes, sharing techniques we&amp;rsquo;d developed together in the preceding 6 years. Behnaz focused on teaching 3D design, fabrication, and soldering, while I taught the students practical math and programming techniques for bringing their work to life.</description></item><item><title>Iridescence</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/iridescence.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/iridescence.html</guid><description>Iridescence is a 3D-printed emotive collar commissioned by the Museum of Science and Industry, Chicago and designed by Behnaz Farahi. It features 200 rotating quills driven by fully custom electromagnetic actuators, and animates in response to the facial expressions and positions of observers (determined via a privacy-preserving facial tracking camera).
I created the software that successfully controlled the wearable for a 15 month exhibition without external intervention. While working on the project, I&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Living Cloud</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/livingcloud.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/livingcloud.html</guid><description>There is a divide between the physical, the rigid world of sensation and direct interaction, and the digital, the fluid world of abstract behaviors and dynamic computation. Over time, this boundary will blur; the digital world will extend into the physical and dynamic media will escape the confines of tiny rectangles in front of our faces. The living and working spaces of the future will adapt to us and our needs.</description></item><item><title>Lynx</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/lynxtool.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/lynxtool.html</guid><description>While spreadsheets are the most approachable programming tools, their design hides the underlying calculations and relationships between cells. What if the calculations, data flows, and data could all be visible?
Before Lynxtool was acquired by Figma, Lynx was a browser-based visual programming environment for data analysts inspired by internal tools Tim Babb helped develop for movies at Pixar for over 10 years.
As the first hire at Lynxtool, I&amp;hellip;
designed, implemented, and documented an in-browser rendering engine and immediate mode user interface toolkit (IMGUI) optimized for Lynx’s unique layout and interaction requirements.</description></item><item><title>Making Faster Systems</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/making-faster-systems.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/making-faster-systems.html</guid><description>This essay is inspired by a 2023 in-person presentation I gave to an audience of software, mechanical, and electrical engineers. While its examples are software-related, the principles apply across domains.
In Structured Programming with go to Statements, Donald E. Knuth wrote &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;premature optimization is the root of all evil&amp;rdquo;, and people have been misquoting him ever since. They tend to miss both what he meant by &amp;ldquo;premature&amp;rdquo; and what has changed since he wrote those words in 1974.</description></item><item><title>Mesolite</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/mesolite.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/mesolite.html</guid><description> In under 130 hours, I prototyped, architected, and developed the control software for Mesolite, an emotive display case commissioned by Adidas and designed by Behnaz Farahi. I used tricks from game development to reduce iteration bottlenecks and improve performance 20x.
Along the way, I&amp;hellip;
learned how to use a Raspberry Pi and used it to create a wifi-enabled realtime monitoring and simulation interface learned about servo motors and built a 30-second calibration tool using the dials on a MIDI controller empowered a procedural animator, Mitch Mastroni, to orchestrate the individual and collective behavior of over a thousand color-changing lights in realtime based on the positions and facial expressions of nearby observers designed protocols to coordinate communication between four microcontrollers and a Raspberry Pi</description></item><item><title>Octobo</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/octobo.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/octobo.html</guid><description> Octobo is a plush soft robot that helps children from 0-7 years old learn the alphabet, spelling, rhythm, and the foundations of STEM education.
Yuting Su designed Octobo at USC. As the sole developer on her thesis project team, I&amp;hellip;
created the microcontroller software, BLE-based communication protocol, and iPad app that allow the toy to interact with children worked with Yuting to evaluate microcontrollers and sensors for the toy&amp;rsquo;s prototype showcased the toy at events helped Yuting in discussions with potential manufacturers</description></item><item><title>Olin Radical Gameplay Initiative</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/gameplayinitiative.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/gameplayinitiative.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pix.</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/pix.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/pix.html</guid><description>In 2012, @notch, the creator of Minecraft, started working on 0x10c, a space game in which players could program virtual spaceships with &amp;ldquo;DCPU-16&amp;rdquo; processors.
Shortly after it was announced, I teamed up with some students in my Computer Architecture class at Olin to create Pix, a 16-bit arcade game that would have run on these virtual processors. Although @notch has since cancelled 0x10c, you can still play Pix in an online emulator.</description></item><item><title>pyShiva</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/pyshiva.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/pyshiva.html</guid><description>Getting computers to draw simple 2d graphics quickly used to be much easier than it is now. Graphics cards are great at drawing triangles but need to be taught to create more complex or organic shapes.
Lots of artists use Processing, but that language has all of the verbosity and incidental complexity of Java with hidden state and complexity approaching OpenGL. Why should an interactive artist need to understand transformation matrices in order to rotate shapes on the screen?</description></item><item><title>Returning the Gaze</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/returning-the-gaze.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/returning-the-gaze.html</guid><description>Returning the Gaze is a robotics installation by Behnaz Farahi, supported by Universal Robots, and commissioned by fashion label ANNAKIKI for its cyborg-themed Milan Fashion Week 2022.
I worked closely with Behnaz to develop the high concept of the project: a fashion model cybernetically enhanced rather than controlled by technology stares back at an audience primed to be the watchers at a fashion show. We prototyped many different design directions before creating what Georgina McWhirter of Interior Design calls</description></item><item><title>Tendar</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/tendar.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/tendar.html</guid><description> Tendar is an award-winning augmented reality game critique of machine learning in the guise of a pet simulation narrative game. It was backed by Google, created by Tender Claws, and featured at Sundance New Frontiers 2018.
I created early game prototypes, developed the game&amp;rsquo;s overall architecture, and implemented core gameplay systems. I also&amp;hellip;
developed and integrated native Android plugins to identify real world objects, faces, and emotions from live camera feeds worked with contacts at Google to refine prerelease AR technologies helped create procedural animations for the game&amp;rsquo;s central character created in-house tools to accelerate artist, writer, and game designer workflows</description></item><item><title>Tetheron</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/tetheron.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/tetheron.html</guid><description>Tetheron is a frantic 2-6 player competitive arcade game in which you swing around a destructible physics environment by tethering onto obstacles and other players. We&amp;rsquo;re developing the game as part of Richard Lemarchand&amp;rsquo;s Experimental Games class at the University of Southern California&amp;rsquo;s Interactive Media and Games graduate program and hope to release it soon.
To stay up to date with development, visit tetheron.com and follow us on twitter @tetheron.</description></item><item><title>The Doppler Effect</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/doppler.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/doppler.html</guid><description>Learning science from a textbook is usually pretty boring. In 2010, Ars Technica hosted a competition to solicit science explanations that high school students would actually enjoy.
During my first year at Olin College of Engineering, I created and led a small team to make The Doppler Effect, a fun educational video that explains why the sounds cars make on a highway change pitch as they pass by. We became the winners of the Ars Science Video Contest, Physical Sciences Division.</description></item><item><title>The Under Presents</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/tup.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/tup.html</guid><description>The Under Presents is an ambitious immersive multiplayer live theater game experience backed by Oculus and created by Tender Claws. It was featured at Sundance Film Festival and Indiecade and developed a dedicated online community. The Under Presents was Tender Claws' most ambitious project to date and its first time making an online multiplayer experience.
I taught myself the Go programming language and used it to create the game&amp;rsquo;s matchmaking server, online administrator portal, and live actor management interface from the ground up, carefully documenting the rationale behind every implementation decision along the way.</description></item><item><title>Timeline</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/timeline.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/timeline.html</guid><description>In 2012, I studied makers who use shared workspaces as part of an immersive exploration of user-oriented collaborative design. My design team used an applied ethnography approach to identify a compelling need and conceptualize a future solution to fulfill that need.
We visited &amp;ldquo;makerspaces&amp;rdquo; around Boston, observed makers at work, conducted in-depth interviews, created people portraits, developed personas, generated hundreds of ideas, and iterated on the most promising by working with our stakeholders though co-design techniques.</description></item><item><title>VILA</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/vila.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/vila.html</guid><description>Programming is seriously broken. Becoming a programmer is hard, but not because solving problems computationally is inherently difficult. Becoming a programmer is hard because it involves so much cognitive friction. Programming today means simulating a computer in your head when you already have one in front of you. Programming today means dealing with the incidental complexity of poorly designed programming tools and archaic mental models.
I&amp;rsquo;ve become so frustrated with programming that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to stop merely thinking about how much better it could be.</description></item><item><title>VVR</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/vvr.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/vvr.html</guid><description>Virtual Virtual Reality is an award-winning VR game with 50k+ installs and majority 5-star ratings. I helped develop the game&amp;rsquo;s prize-winning first prototype during a game jam. While I was in grad school, Tender Claws turned it into a full game for Google&amp;rsquo;s Daydream VR headset with backing from Google. After I graduated, I joined Tender Claws full-time and rearchitected the game to support different VR/desktop/console platforms and control schemes.</description></item><item><title>Zoolemma!</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/zoolemma.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/zoolemma.html</guid><description>Zoolemma! is a prototype for a purely strategic 2-3 player boardgame with two unique properties:
you can move your opponents' pieces as well as your own you all plan each move simultaneously to minimize player inaction Every time a piece moves on the board, the space upon which it lands determines how a different player&amp;rsquo;s piece moves. This mechanic leads to some very interesting meta strategies as players try to predict where their pieces will be during their turns and try to manipulate other players into helping them win.</description></item></channel></rss>