<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>robotics on Julian Ceipek</title><link>//jceipek.com/categories/robotics.html</link><description>Recent content in robotics on Julian Ceipek</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//jceipek.com/categories/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aurora</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/aurora.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/aurora.html</guid><description>Aurora is an interactive kinetic ceiling that changes its configuration in response to what is happening in the space beneath it.
I developed software to simulate the ceiling virtually while also driving the motors that control it physically. I worked closely with Behnaz Farahi to design depth camera-driven procedural animations for the ceiling.</description></item><item><title>Blindness</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/blindness.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/blindness.html</guid><description>Returning the Gaze is a robotics installation by Behnaz Farahi, supported by Universal Robots, and commissioned by fashion label ANNAKIKI for its cyborg-themed Milan Fashion Week 2022.
I worked closely with Behnaz to develop the high concept of the project: a fashion model cybernetically enhanced rather than controlled by technology stares back at an audience primed to be the watchers at a fashion show. We prototyped many different design directions before creating what Georgina McWhirter of Interior Design calls</description></item><item><title>Caress of the Gaze</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/cog.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/cog.html</guid><description>Behnaz Farahi&amp;rsquo;s Caress of the Gaze is a dress that changes shape when people look at it, exploring social issues such as intimacy, gender and personal identity. It has been featured by outlets including Wired, CNN, The Guardian, BBC News, Engadget, and CNET.
I developed the control software for the final iteration of the dress. Along the way, I&amp;hellip;
created a reusable C library to communicate with a privacy-preserving face tracking camera, which I&amp;rsquo;ve since used on many other projects worked closely with Behnaz to design reactive procedural animations driven by gaze-tracking data learned how to control shape memory alloy actuators that expand and contract like muscles</description></item><item><title>Iridescence</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/iridescence.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/iridescence.html</guid><description>Iridescence is a 3D-printed emotive collar commissioned by the Museum of Science and Industry, Chicago and designed by Behnaz Farahi. It features 200 rotating quills driven by fully custom electromagnetic actuators, and animates in response to the facial expressions and positions of observers (determined via a privacy-preserving facial tracking camera).
I created the software that successfully controlled the wearable for a 15 month exhibition without external intervention. While working on the project, I&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Mesolite</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/mesolite.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/mesolite.html</guid><description> In under 130 hours, I prototyped, architected, and developed the control software for Mesolite, an emotive display case commissioned by Adidas and designed by Behnaz Farahi. I used tricks from game development to reduce iteration bottlenecks and improve performance 20x.
Along the way, I&amp;hellip;
learned how to use a Raspberry Pi and used it to create a wifi-enabled realtime monitoring and simulation interface learned about servo motors and built a 30-second calibration tool using the dials on a MIDI controller empowered a procedural animator, Mitch Mastroni, to orchestrate the individual and collective behavior of over a thousand color-changing lights in realtime based on the positions and facial expressions of nearby observers designed protocols to coordinate communication between four microcontrollers and a Raspberry Pi</description></item><item><title>Octobo</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/octobo.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/octobo.html</guid><description> Octobo is a plush soft robot that helps children from 0-7 years old learn the alphabet, spelling, rhythm, and the foundations of STEM education.
Yuting Su designed Octobo at USC. As the sole developer on her thesis project team, I&amp;hellip;
created the microcontroller software, BLE-based communication protocol, and iPad app that allow the toy to interact with children worked with Yuting to evaluate microcontrollers and sensors for the toy&amp;rsquo;s prototype showcased the toy at events helped Yuting in discussions with potential manufacturers</description></item><item><title>Returning the Gaze</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/returning-the-gaze.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/returning-the-gaze.html</guid><description>Returning the Gaze is a robotics installation by Behnaz Farahi, supported by Universal Robots, and commissioned by fashion label ANNAKIKI for its cyborg-themed Milan Fashion Week 2022.
I worked closely with Behnaz to develop the high concept of the project: a fashion model cybernetically enhanced rather than controlled by technology stares back at an audience primed to be the watchers at a fashion show. We prototyped many different design directions before creating what Georgina McWhirter of Interior Design calls</description></item></channel></rss>