<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>game on Julian Ceipek</title><link>//jceipek.com/categories/game.html</link><description>Recent content in game on Julian Ceipek</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//jceipek.com/categories/game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tendar</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/tendar.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/tendar.html</guid><description> Tendar is an award-winning augmented reality game critique of machine learning in the guise of a pet simulation narrative game. It was backed by Google, created by Tender Claws, and featured at Sundance New Frontiers 2018.
I created early game prototypes, developed the game&amp;rsquo;s overall architecture, and implemented core gameplay systems. I also&amp;hellip;
developed and integrated native Android plugins to identify real world objects, faces, and emotions from live camera feeds worked with contacts at Google to refine prerelease AR technologies helped create procedural animations for the game&amp;rsquo;s central character created in-house tools to accelerate artist, writer, and game designer workflows</description></item><item><title>The Under Presents</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/tup.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/tup.html</guid><description>The Under Presents is an ambitious immersive multiplayer live theater game experience backed by Oculus and created by Tender Claws. It was featured at Sundance Film Festival and Indiecade and developed a dedicated online community. The Under Presents was Tender Claws&amp;rsquo; most ambitious project to date and its first time making an online multiplayer experience.
I taught myself the Go programming language and used it to create the game&amp;rsquo;s matchmaking server, online administrator portal, and live actor management interface from the ground up, carefully documenting the rationale behind every implementation decision along the way.</description></item><item><title>VVR</title><link>//jceipek.com/projects/vvr.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//jceipek.com/projects/vvr.html</guid><description>Virtual Virtual Reality is an award-winning VR game with 50k+ installs and majority 5-star ratings. I helped develop the game&amp;rsquo;s prize-winning first prototype during a game jam. While I was in grad school, Tender Claws turned it into a full game for Google&amp;rsquo;s Daydream VR headset with backing from Google. After I graduated, I joined Tender Claws full-time and rearchitected the game to support different VR/desktop/console platforms and control schemes.</description></item></channel></rss>